[whirring, beeping]
[smooth instrumental music playing]
[engine starts, revs]
[Jerry] This is a 1964 Aston Martin DB5
in silver birch
with an all-aluminum
280-horsepower straight-six.
Yes, yes. Oh, yes.
This is the one.
No other car could possibly have been
exactly what James Bond needed
when it was time to save the world.
It's dapper, it's dashing,
it's distinguished,
it's deadly.
In comedy, we are also
out to save the world.
And sometimes,
a very special agent is required.
Someone who can take written material
and turn it into a very deadly weapon.
Very few people
possess these special skills.
My guest today
is one of those very special agents,
Miss Julia Louis-Dreyfus.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
[musical flourish]
[laughing]
[Jerry] Remember this? You remember this?
-Remember this?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
[Jerry laughing]
-Okay, so...
-Oh, boy.
-I'm nervous.
-Don't give me the work face.
-Okay.
[smooth instrumental music playing]
[exclaiming excitedly] Oh! Oh-ho-ho!
[Julia] Oh, my God.
It's unbelievable-looking.
-It's chic.
-[Jerry] Yeah, well, that's you.
-Thanks, that's nice of you.
-You're welcome.
-[Julia] Look at the wheels.
-[Jerry] I know. Borrani wires.
-That's what I was gonna say.
-Yeah. [chuckles]
It's English, high-end,
'cause you are the James Bond of comedy.
Whatever the mission,
whatever the situation,
you come in and kill it.
-That is, first of all...
-Right?
...the nicest thing
anyone has ever said to me.
I have never seen anything
quite like this. Isn't it unbelievable?
Oh, my God! Look at this thing.
[man, honks horn]
Hey, Jerry, I'll trade ya.
[Julia laughing]
I'm so tired of that line.
-So tired of it.
-You poor man.
[chuckling]
You know what else
I can't take another second of?
One, two...
Just take the picture.
Nothing happens on three, okay?
I'm not gonna get happy on three.
[smooth instrumental music playing]
[Julia] I'm not a car person,
but I must say
that it's so lovely, this car.
How about this?
They could let this go for a song.
[Julia] Let me tell you something.
This house is like the worst of a woman
who lives in Los Angeles,
constantly doing surgery,
and is unrecognizable and hideous.
One of those horrible housewives
or something.
That would've been a much better title
than The Real Housewives.
Those Horrible Housewives.
-[horn honks]
-[Julia] Oh. Okay.
-What's happening?
-[chuckling]
I'm so sorry.
We're doing the Seinfeld reunion.
And you're not in it.
[Julia laughs] Bye.
See, because you're so charming,
you got away with insulting her,
-profoundly.
-Thank you.
Do you think I'm nice?
I think you can be nice.
Anyone can be nice.
Hitler can be nice.
Well, you're nicer than Hitler.
-Oh, hey! How's it going?
-[woman] Hey!
-Oh, my God!
-[Julia] How hilarious.
You don't bring any attention to yourself.
-[Jerry laughing]
-[Julia] Okay.
That was Hilary Swank...
-I know!
-...and I guess we must live in Hollywood.
[upbeat music playing]
[Julia] Do you remember...
I love anything you say that starts with,
"Do you remember?"
[laughing]
Do you remember when I was about
five months pregnant with my youngest,
and big as a house, and you came up--
-Okay. Here we go.
-I know where this is going.
And you came up to me, and you said,
"Hey, we had a great idea.
How about if we write it in this season
that Elaine just gets fat?"
Don't get in a car accident
from that reminiscence. Hi.
And so, what did I do?
Burst into tears. Automatic.
It was like a death sentence.
So, there are two things
I have to say about that.
One is, you have
no interpersonal communication skills.
-That's not true.
-The second thing is,
it was a great idea
and we should've done it.
[gasps]
-I can't believe you're saying this.
-It would've been a great storyline.
Yeah, it would've been pretty funny.
And it really shows
what a great comic actress you are,
that you thought about it,
and eventually got to,
"That was the funny direction to go."
Yeah. I actually... I regret it.
[upbeat music playing]
[inaudible]
The other thing that I think about
is what happened to my horse.
Hey, how did my... [giggles]
[Julia] And you know who that is, right?
It's Tracy Letts,
who went on to win the Pulitzer Prize.
He wrote August: Osage County.
Yes. That is exactly right.
I said, "Hey, how'd my horse do?"
[chuckles] And he said...
He had to be shot.
Which, to this day, is so deeply funny.
Why do you think it's so funny?
Because it's so teed up for hope,
and that's why it's funny.
-"Line!" That's another thing I remember.
-[Jerry laughing]
[Julia laughing]
-"Line!"
-[laughing]
Like it's the other person's fault...
-Yeah.
-...that I forgot my line.
[both laughing]
See, we had fun on that show.
[upbeat jazz music playing]
-I'm so happy to see you.
-Remember when we were doing--
-The parking garage?
How did you know I was gonna say that?
Because I knew you were gonna say it.
Did you ever want to work at a coffee bar?
[Julia]
No, but I was an ice cream scooper.
-But I...
-Oh, yeah. [laughs]
Yeah, that lasted a week.
What happened was,
whoever was working the cash register
had to leave or something,
so they said, "Will you
go work the cash register?"
And I said, "Okay."
I don't know how to work the register.
The cash register ran out of tape.
And the drawer was open,
so I went to go find somebody to help me,
and I sort of walked away
with the register open.
The manager, who I think was 18,
but it seemed like he was 40,
came out, and he says,
"Do you have any idea
what you just did wrong, young lady?"
Which I just... [mimicking sobbing]
Started crying so hard.
[Jerry] You cry a lot.
[Julia] Look. Isn't that gorgeous?
[Jerry] "I lay this [bleep] before you."
Remember that one?
Jason would finish his speech,
and he would do this.
I go, "What does that mean?"
-He goes, "I lay this [bleep] before you."
-Yeah.
Look at this.
[softly] Wow, Julia, this is really good.
How can you tell it's so good,
just 'cause it feels and looks good?
Yes. Feels good, looks good, is good.
[laughing]
-Cheers.
Could be a little hotter.
-I was gonna say that.
-What can they do?
-Are you gonna get into this?
-[sighs]
It's so good.
It just needs a little more heat.
What do you think?
Now we'll see who the nice person is...
Oh, look at this. There she goes.
-[Julia] Can we ask a favor?
-Yes.
Is it possible to heat these up?
'Cause this was too cool.
I thought I was nice.
The guy's calling me an asshole
behind my back.
That is the right way
to call someone an asshole.
Behind their back.
-You can put that in your book of...
-Asshole manners.
You remember in that cartoon
I told you that I loved?
It's a guy painting a landscape,
and a car is going by,
and the guy is sticking his bare ass
out of the window,
and the balloon says,
"Hey, Ottist!" O-T-T-I-S-T.
[Julia] "Paint this!"
The breadth of quality
in the humor that you appreciate
is the widest of anyone
that I've ever met.
[server] Two hot cappuccinos for you.
-[Julia] Thanks so much.
-[Jerry] Wow.
If this isn't warm enough,
guess who's going up to get a third one?
I'm looking at him.
[upbeat jazz music playing]
Marriage just cracks me up.
-How long have you been married now?
-Fifteen years.
Really? You had always said
you would never get married.
I still feel that way.
But there was quite a bit of work
that my wife, God bless her, had to do.
That was a grimy job.
Thigh-high boots
and a lot of long tools that grind,
and a lot of hazmat bags.
Just take this out of here.
This has all gotta go.
I find that fights, for us,
start with something absolutely minute.
Like...
"Why are there coffee grinds here?"
I can't help myself, you understand?
I just love the timing on the table hit.
Not on the "here," but on the "why."
-"Why are there coffee grinds here?"
[both chuckling]
I got another one to tell you.
But it was a big birthday.
He gave me this big present
of a suitcase.
And I didn't respond to that
particularly well.
-No.
-I don't want a suitcase.
If I need a suitcase,
I'm just gonna buy it for myself.
I don't really think of this as a gift.
-Sorry, Brad. Mm-mm.
-No.
-And, by the way, in his defense--
-In his defense...
-Bradley.
No. I go out for, like, a run or something
to blow off steam.
I come back, on the dining room table,
the yellow book is open to florists.
Just wide open, "Florists."
In his defense, he's gotten crazy better.
-How many years you married?
-Twenty-eight years in June.
So, go like that for good luck.
[upbeat jazz playing]
But let me just go back to the moment
you and I met,
-at Ren-Mar.
-Ren-Mar, Desilu Studios.
Formerly Desilu Studios.
I remember seeing you,
and you were eating cereal that day.
You were eating cereal,
and we were talking.
I just thought, "He's such a relaxed guy."
And then when we went
and we read that scene,
"Where do you wanna go?"
"I don't care, I'm not hungry."
"Long as I don't have to talk."
-Right?
-Right.
Could go to one of those cappuccino
places. They let you sit there.
I'll go if I don't have to talk.
Nothing had ever been
written like that before.
-Like, it was just a conversation...
-Right.
...as opposed to a setup,
punchline, setup, punchline.
-Right.
-And I just remember thinking,
"This is so nice and relaxed.
It's got such a different vibe.
It'll never go."
-Well, it almost didn't.
-I know.
[upbeat jazz playing]
So, what do these do?
They're progressives.
Wow, you look great.
[both laughing]
Look down to the bottom of the lens.
[Julia laughing]
There's a vat of coffee.
This is the weakest prescription
of glasses
-I have ever seen in my life.
-You're wrong.
I'm fine with that, too.
There's marriage, A to Z.
"You're wrong." "I'm fine."
[both laughing]
If I'm right, I know I'm right.
And I know the right place
for coffee grounds.
[Julia laughing]
Not there.
Let me get this.
Thank you.
[uptempo instrumental music playing]
[inaudible]
Oh, look at that pretty dog. Hi.
-[Julia] What's your doggy's name?
-[woman] Candy.
[Julia] She's a therapy dog?
Does Candy have time for Jerry right now?
-[woman] Yes, it's five minutes.
-Can you squeeze me in?
[Julia] Bye, Candy. See you.
Every woman today lives like Cleopatra.
You got that right.
The emollients,
and salves, and balms, and oils.
Just swimming in goo.
-[Julia] You hungry?
-[Jerry] I could always eat.
-Wanna go get something to eat?
-Where do you wanna go?
Don't care, I'm not hungry.
-[Jerry] Do you wanna eat?
-I don't know.
I mean, I'll eat--
If you wanna eat, I'll eat with you.
[jazz music continues]
I know how much you love your bed.
Is that still your very favorite place
to be, in bed?
I can't believe you're saying that.
What do you mean?
You think I don't know you?
-We chatted a bit over ten years.
-Seventy-five years.
You said the only way
you would ever do another TV series
is if you could do it from your bed.
[Jerry laughs]
-That's what you said.
-Uh-huh.
-What's your favorite place?
-Santa Barbara.
-Favorite cookie?
-Chocolate-chip.
You're a thrill a minute.
[laughing]
-What's your favorite brand of deodorant?
-Mitchum.
It's very bad for you, deodorant.
I actually try not to wear it
unless I'm working.
I know.
[laughing]
I'm working now.
But don't you like to shop
on the Internet?
Do you go on NET-A-PORTER like my wife?
You love it, right?
All you good-taste girls love that.
It's good.
Except ask her this question for me.
They send me a thing,
I click on it right away,
-and it already says sold out.
-When you get a thing from them...
-And you click on it.
-...and you click on it...
And does she go to it, and it immediately
says X, Y, and Z are sold out?
And then it'll say sold out?
Do you get the VIP preview?
Ah! See?
Can I talk to her?
Hi, Jessica. It's Julia.
What VIP preview?
[laughs heartily]
I'm just clicking onto them right now.
[sighs, softly] I'm gonna
need some more coffee.
Who is buying this crap?
-No offense.
-And it's...
I'm getting a thing from Jerry
saying wrap it up.
Oh, yeah, and by the way,
thank you for training him
to become a human being.
'Cause what I was dealing with was, um...
Well, anyway. Okay, take care.
You're really making me miss the show now.
I know, right?
The laughs we used to have hanging out.
-The laughs.
-Yeah.
It is so fun to be reminded
of how funny you are.
Oh, likewise.
[upbeat music playing]
What about when we were
at that restaurant?
-Ah!
-Will you ever forget it?
-Never.
We were in New York because
we did the Rolling Stone cover shoot.
And then we thought,
"We'll go out, and we'll all eat together,
and we'll sit out on the sidewalk,
and people will freak out!"
-And not a soul, except for one.
-Well. One.
-One homeless man.
-God bless him.
-Yeah, he was a big fan.
[smooth instrumental music playing]
[Julia] Here's something
my mom said to me,
and I think it's very true,
in terms of happiness.
You have to always have
something to look forward to.
-Hmm.
-And it can be a very minor thing,
and it can be a major thing,
but you always have to have
something you're looking forward to next.
Well, what are you looking forward to
right now?
Getting the hell out of this car.
[both laughing]
-Oh, that was a heavy peach.
-[Julia laughs]
That was a heavy peach, and she picked it.
[giggles]
[Julia] What are you looking forward to?
[Jerry] Getting out of this car.
[both laughing]
Thanks for inviting me to be on your show.
-I think this show is great.
-Thank you.
-And I love ya.
-I love you, too.
I really do.